I'm Andy Hook, a web designer & front-end developer from East Sussex.

Telephone 07980450299

Email contact@andy-hook.co.uk

Portfolio andy-hook.co.uk

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/andyahook

Profile

A dedicated, enthusiastic and highly-motivated web professional with over 5 years commercial design and development experience. Formally educated in fine art, illustration and graphic design, I focus on delivering compelling visuals and performant code for the web.

Skills Responsive Web Design & Digital Illustration

More than 10 years experience working with the Adobe suite of creative applications. Extensive knowledge of web asset creation and optimisation. Experienced with 3d modelling packages and 2d texturing techniques. Skills include:

- Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, inDesign, Animate
- 3ds Max

Front-End Development

Over 5 years experience delivering clean, modular front-end code. Perfecting scalable, maintainable CSS architecture using the latest pre-processor features and design methodologies. Experienced in the use of client side build tools to assist work-flow efficiency. Technical knowledge includes:

- HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, SMACSS, OOCSS, BEM
- Javascript, jQuery, RequireJS, Modernizr, Grunt, Gulp
- Handlebars, ERB, PHP Templating, Wordpress, Metalsmith, Middleman
- GIT, JIRA, Confluence



Experience

Web Designer & Front-End Developer

The Jamieson Consultancy

January 2012 - January 2016

Working within a small, talented team of web professionals I took lead on a variety of creative, design and development projects. These include the implementation of modular front-end component libraries, email campaign design, branding, identity and style guide creation.

I was also an advocate for the maintenance of project documentation, front-end blueprints, boilerplates, a mentor to peers on front-end coding style, best practices, cross platform considerations, performance, work-flow and front-end tooling.

Illustrator & Graphic Designer

Freelance

July 2009 - January 2012

Provided a range of high quality graphic design and digital illustration services, much of my work focused on brand design and digital artwork for a variety of small to medium sized businesses.

Education

Bsc Honours Degree, Games Technology

The University of Portsmouth

September 2006 - July 2009

Functional design and concept illustration with a focus on original character and object art, performance conscious modelling, texture mapping, 3d sculpting and high quality rendering. Studies also covered the use of game mechanics, direction, feedback loop, user experience, interface and the real-time art asset pipeline.

Foundation Diploma, Art and Design

Hastings College of Art and Technology

July 2005 - January 2006

Art studies to build upon core design and illustration abilities. Modules included life studies, the foundations of visual design, colour theory, expression through drawing, painting, art history, etching with wax, acid and press.

National Diploma, Multimedia

Hastings College of Art and Technology

July 2003 - January 2005

Web design, life drawing, traditional and digital animation, typography, visual composition, introduction to programming with JavaScript, video capture, editing, encoding and audio mixing.